Jasmin Hamilton

JasminMHamilton@icloud.com

Portfolio: https://www.behance.net/jasminhamilton

Philadelphia, PA United States. Open to relocating and working remote.

CAREER SUMMARY

A creative, team-oriented **UI/UX designer** with 8 + years of experience in brand development, UX research, and design and project management within the music and entertainment industry. A creative with a niche in developing concepts to design for brands and digital content. Utilizing the user centered design approach, creating products with intent for potential users or customers.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

User Research, User Experience Design (UED), Prototyping, Storyboarding, User Testing, Mockups, Visual Design, Wireframes, User Flow, Graphic Design, Interaction Design, Project Management, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Web Design.

DESIGN PROJECTS

On Tour — *UI Design* (*View Project Here*)

Created a Fintech app entitled On Tour. On Tour is a money saving tool for Indie artists, that provides strategy and budget plans to assist artists with their music career progression. Indie artists undergo an onboarding process before creating an account, providing metrics based on their career's revenue, so On Tour can provide personalized information and financial plans.

Bespoke — UI Design, Iconography & Branding (View Project Here)

Designed an ecommerce sales app for vintage clothing. Created branding and style guide based on user personas of the target audience.

Got Crypto? — *UI Design, Graphic Design & Style Guide* (View Project Here)

Developed a Cryptocurrency learning app that allows users new to the world of Crypto to ask a question, simulate converting crypto and take subject-based courses to educate themselves. Focused on user flows having simple functionality, avoiding users having to learn additional aspects outside the subject matter of cryptocurrency.

FoodX — *UX Research & Interviews, Prototype Testing an UI Design* (*View Project Here*)
Built an in-depth UX case study for a recipe app, titled Foodx. FoodX is a recipe app that provides users with

food experiences that are unorthodox to recipe digital products. User interviews were conducted in addition to multiple iterations of prototype testing to ensure usability.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Manager, Synergetic, Bensalem, PA JULY 2022 - PRESENT

- Create and organize training sessions, which improve technicians' skill sets in audio, video, and lighting for lead role positions.
- Develop effective strategic plans for staff, including event logistics and coordination, based on proactive communication with Project Managers and Account Managers.
- Schedule events 2-3 weeks out and make events with high demand priority, producing AV productions with high levels of success for all clients.
- Source technicians from in network or outsource from staffing companies. Vet technicians based on skill sets needed for a particular job and placing them accordingly.

• Advocate for AV technicians by addressing their needs, concerns and suggestions, and implementing changes with management to create a thriving culture for all employees.

Creative Director/Owner, One Lion Hundred Sheep, Philadelphia, PA IANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

- Design unique graphics based on the brand's vision and narrative.
- Implement changes, and redesign as needed for designs progression to final state, which reduces overhead cost for designs and improves clients' satisfaction.
- Create apparel mockups and tech packs using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop, to reduce margins for error.
- Work with manufacturer production teams to keep brand consistency across all mediums.
 Distribute a style guide for all apparel, which includes logo size variations, typography, and color palette to printers and manufactures.
- Conduct Quality Control for all products and apparel with focus on fabric quality, colors, and element placements, providing consistency with brand standards & guidelines.
- Provide authentic customer service by communicating with customers, keeping them well informed and being transparent regarding any delays or out of stock items.
- Strategize marketing campaigns with social media influencers, fashion influencers, and content creators to connect the brand with the target audience and increase sales.

Project Manager, Synergetic, Bensalem, PA JULY 2019 - MARCH 2020

- Managed audio-visual productions for social and corporate events, which include audio, video, lighting and staging.
- Created proposals for clients with options that are based on their budget and provided their desired outcomes with high standard productions.
- Built relationships with venue sales team, property managers, and banquet management by attending weekly meetings and always keeping an open line of communication.
- Coordinated events' setup through effective communication with the production team, explaining the scope of work, and assigning techs to tasks promoting teamwork.

Freelance AV Tech & Events Coordinator, Kinney Group Events, United States MAY 2014 - JUNE 2022

- AV liaison or consultant on behalf of venues, organizing AV equipment and services customized to clients' requests and desires for events.
- Provide great customer service to clients by quickly troubling shooting when issues occur, being available to provide answers, and having a firm handle on managing productions.

EDUCATION

UI/UX Design Certification, CareerFoundry, Jan 2023

Developed an understanding of visual design principles, while designing for different platforms including wireframing, mockups, prototype testing, branding, and UX research & design.

Audio Production, BS, Art Institute of Philadelphia, Dec 2013

Design Tools

Figma, Adobe XD, Slack, After effects, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, InVision